Guide to the Janet Greene Papers on the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project WAG.233
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Janet Greene Papers on the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project
1960-2003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Greene, Janet Wells
WAG.233
3.75 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes and one half manuscript box
155.20 Megabytes in 99 electronic files
Janet Wells Greene was director of the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project at New York University's Tamiment Library 1996-2002. This collection consists of her paper and electronic records from the project, as well as some earlier project records, from 1979 through 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was created by Janet Greene in the course of her work as director of the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.264.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in their original order, alphabetically within two series: Labor organizations and Office records.
Biographical/Historical Note
Janet Wells Greene was director of the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project at New York University's Tamiment Library from 1996 to 2002. She received her PhD in American History from NYU.
The Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project, named for the late New York City labor leader, located records of labor organizations throughout New York State to preserve them for future generations of unionists and scholars. Beginning in 1984, Tamiment Library staff surveyed or oversaw survey of records of more than 700 New York labor organizations, preserved some 200 collections through microfilming or accessioning, trained more than 200 union records-keepers, and conducted scores of oral history interviews with labor veterans.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of Janet Greene's papers from the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project at NYU, which ran from 1984 through 2003. Materials document the origins of the project and include background papers, grant applications, and reports. The collection also contains documents from and information on several labor organizations that participated in the project.
Document types include correspondence, surveys, reports, publications, publicity materials, deeds of gift, and photographs. Many items are photocopies of originals, including photographs. The collection also contains the following digitized and born-digital materials: a labor union scrapbook with photos, a bibliography for "Women in the Trades", Janet Greene's "personal NHPRC files", and her 1996 course syllabus.
Appraisal
Student curriculum vitae, resumes, and employment documents were de-accessioned November 2019.
Labor -- History; Labor unions; Oral histories (literary works); New York University
- Series I: Labor Organizations, 1960-2002; 1 Linear Feet; 79.96 Megabytes in 30 electronic files
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains records from the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project's collaboration with several labor organizations and includes correspondence, background materials, forms, letters of agreement, and some oral history interviw transcripts.
  - Building and Construction Trades Council - Ironworkers, 1985-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1-29)
  - Hotel Trades Council, 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 1-7, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_233_ER_2)
  - Labor Council Affiliates - Sheetmetal Workers, 1960-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1-29, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_233_ER_3)
  - Bricklayers' Local Scrapbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 17, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_233_ER_1)
- Series II: Office records, 1979-2002; 2.75 Linear Feet; 75.24 Megabytes in 69 electronic files
  Series II contains administrative records and background materials from the Harry Van Arsdale Labor History Project. Included are funding and grant application records, correspondence with staff and student workers administering the project, project forms and mailing lists, clippings and publicity materials, and syllabi from related courses taught by Janet Greene.
  - Bibliography - Clippings, 1996-2002 (Box 2)
  - Clippings - Indoor Air Quality Study, 1990-2002 (Box 3)
  - Internship Syllabi - Offsite storage, 1996-2002 (Box 4, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_233_ER_4)
  - OPEL: Ordinary People, Extraordinary Lives, 1996-2001 (Box 5, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_233_ER_5)
  - OPEL - Reports, 1979-2002 (Box 6)
  - Rubin, Don - World Trade Center, 1984-2002 (Box 7, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_WAG_233_ER_7)